# PRADNESH SANDERAN

COMPUTER SCIENCE STUDENT

### Profile

Self-assured computer science student and team leader with diverse experience utilizing programming languages for assignments and projects and fluid understanding of object oriented programming languages(Java) and functional programming languages (Haskell). Highly trained in various technology environments.

# Experience

## **TEACHER**

## Rumah Hope, Kuala Lumpur | 2018 - 2019

I volunteered as a teacher at the Rumah Hope Children's Home in Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia. Here, I taught the children, whose ages ranged from 4 to 16 years old, science and English every Friday for the years 2018 and 2019.

# **VOLUNTEERED AT THE ANIMAL SHELTER**

SPCA Kajang, Kuala Lumpur - 2016

I volunteered at the SPCA where i had cleaned the cages and kennels of the dogs and cats. I had also given the dogs a bath and fed them.

## **CO-FOUNDER OF A SOUP KITCHEN**

Indrani's Kitchen, Kuala Lumpur | 2013 - Present

In 2013, me and 4 others co-founded a soup kitchen called Indrani's Kadai where on the first Saturday of every month we would hand out food to the homeless around the Kuala Lumpur City Centre

# Education

# **BSC COMPUTER SCIENCE**

# University of Edinburgh, Edinburgh | 2019 - 2023

This degree is focused on understanding, designing, implementing and using computing systems, ranging in scale and complexity from the tiny components of a single processor to the globe-spanning internet. It also concerns the practical techniques of programming computers to solve real and difficult problems with links to other subjects, from electronics, physics, mathematics and various others

### **A-LEVLES**

HELP Academy, Kuala Lumpur | 2018 - 2019 4A

### Personal information

#### Gender

Male

#### Residence

11/4 New Arthur Place, Edinburgh, Scotland

## **Nationality**

Malaysian

## **Achievements**



#### **A LEVELS**

4A

# SCHOOL LEAVING CERTIFICATE **(SPM)**

7A+ 2A 1B+

## Skills

## **Programming Languages**

Java Haskell Javascript



## **Softwares**

Microsoft Word Microsoft Powerpoint Microsoft excel Adobe Photoshop Adobe Lightroom Adobe Premier Pro



## Languages

English Malay Language Tamil



#### **Professional Skills**

Effective multitasker with outstanding organizational and customer service skills Excellent team building skills, meeting preparation







## Interests

skills



and organization

Event management





## **CO-FOUNDER OF A SOUP KITCHEN**

Indranis Kitchen | 2013 - Present

## **TEACHER AT A CHILDREN'S HOME**

Rumah Hope | 2018 - 2019

## **VOLUNTEERED AT THE ANIMAL SHELTER**

SPCA Kajang - 2016

## PACKED FOOD FOR TYPHOON VICTIMS

Stop Hunger Now - 2014

I had helped pack food packets for the victims of typhoon rammasun in Philippines with Stop Hunger Now

# **Projects**

#### 2020 STUDENT STUDY ASSISTANT

Hello World Hackathon

During the Hello World Hackathon, me and my team built a program that would help people study. if a student uploads a picture of their textbook or any notes to the program, the programs scans the image for keywords that would be related to what the student is studying based on its library. it then does web scrapping to find the most relevant information about that topic from various sources such as wikipedia, google scholar and youtube. it then returns the information to a webpage. the information can then be synthesized and converted to audio. This would help students as it reduces the time spent looking up information as the most relevant information is handed to them. it also helps the visually impaired as the can listen to the audio once the text is synthesized.

### 2020 INSIGHT

Hack The Burgh

Android application written in native Java. This application curates the most sustainable recreational activities that tourists can get in their vicinity, even considering the weather! We aim to make this the only app tourists will ever need. When travellers first come to an unknown city, they probably won't be that familiar with the local weather which might potentially affect their travel plan, so our app can detect the climate based on three indexes: weather, temperature and wind speed to recommend the suitable attractions (categorized as indoor and outdoor) for travellers to visit.





## Contact

#### Contact

- A Edinburgh, United Kingdom
- **\** 07367871017
- pradneshsanderan@gmail.com

#### Social

- in linkedin.com/in/pradnesh-sanderan-70b24b19a
- https://github.com/pradneshsanderan